All right, it's time to talk about that
modulus operator. So, what does it do?
All right, so in order to explain that,
I'm going to take you all the way back
to third or fourth grade math. So, let's
do some division.
Um, if we wanted to see
how many times seven could go into 12,
um, we would say, okay, 7 goes into 12
um, one time evenly. So, we'd say 7* 1.
And so then we'd say 1 * 7, we'd put the
7 there. 12 - 7 gives us 5. And
hopefully you're familiar with how
division works. Um, if we wanted to go
all the way out and figure out what the
decimal place was that comes after this,
we'd put a point. We'd bring a zero down
and then we'd say 7 goes into 50. 7
times. 7 * 7 is 49. And then we'd
subtract and that would give us a 1. And
we keep going from there until we
figured out exactly how many times 7
goes into 12. Well, I have good news for
you. We don't have to go that far.
Um, 7 goes into 12 exactly one time. The
remainder that's left over is this five
down here. So 7 goes into 12 one time
with a remainder of five. This five
right here is the result that using the
modulus operator will give you. So if
you said 12 modulus 7, it would say how
many times does seven evenly go into 12.
Once we figured that out, what's the
remainder? In this case, the remainder
is five. And that is the result of using
the modulus operator. And the next video
I'll show you that in practice.